Guide to the Records of Amnesty International of the USA, Inc.
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series XI: Administration and Operation, 1966-1997
  - Subseries XI.2: Operations, 1966-1995
    - Sub-subseries XI.2.4: General Files, 1966-1995
      - International Secretariat (IS)
        - Two-Year Plans
          - 1990 (Box 411, Folder 28)
            (includes AIUSA comments)
        - Units and department within IS, 1991 (Box 411, Folder 29)
      - International Sections--Correspondence, 1988-1989 (Box 411, Folder 30)
      - Investment Committee, 1992-1994 (Box 411, Folder 31)
      - Investment policy, 1993 (Box 411, Folder 32)
      - Legal
        - Correspondence, 1989-1991, (2 Folders) (Box 411, Folder 33-34)
        - Liability for juveniles at AIUSA events, 1989 (Box 411, Folder 35)
      - Letters, 1991 (Box 411, Folder 36)
      - Lobbying
        - 1976-1987, (5 Folders) (Box 411, Folder 37-41)
        - Expenses, 1981-1989 (Box 411, Folder 42)
        - Manual, Undated (Box 411, Folder 43)
        - Training Handbook, circa 1989 (Box 411, Folder 44)
      - Local Groups (Box 412)
        - Chartering/organizing/closing, 1988-1992 (Box 412, Folder 1)
        - Charters/pledge forms, FY 1991 (Box 412, Folder 2)
        - Correspondence, 1992-1994, (2 Folders) (Box 412, Folder 3-4)
        - Federal tax exemption, 1989-1993 (Box 412, Folder 5)
        - Finances
          - 1986-1987, (2 Folders) (Box 412, Folder 6-7)
          - Fundraising, 1986-1994 (Box 412, Folder 8)
          - Group assessment/pledge program, 1988-1991 (Box 412, Folder 9)
          - FY 1990, (5 Folders) (Box 412, Folder 10-14)
          - New Pledge System and Local Group Finance Policy, 1990 (Box 412, Folder 15)
          - Follow-up, 1991 (Box 412, Folder 16)
          - Fundraising for Human Rights by Rebecca Edwards, Stephen King and Dee Ertukel, 1993 (Box 412, Folder 17)
          - Finance Guidelines, 1993-1994, (2 Folders) (Box 412, Folder 18-19)
        - Kulinyi, Sue (Chair of the AC/RMC Steering Committee), 1989-1990 (Box 412, Folder 20)
        - Servicing costs, 1992 (Box 412, Folder 21)
      - Los Angeles--Major fund raising event, 1993, (6 Folders) (Box 412, Folder 22-27)
      - Management Assistance Group, Washington, D.C, 1983, (2 Folders) (Box 412, Folder 28-29)
        (plans for growth and organizational restructuring)
      - Maiman, Evelyn B. (AIUSA comptroller)--"Legal letters," 1979, 1981 (Box 414, Folder 1)
      - Marley, Bob--Memorial Fund, 1993- (Box 414, Folder 2)
      - Memos--Sandosham, 1992-1994 (Box 414, Folder 3)
      - Merchandizing Proposal, 1991-1993 (Box 414, Folder 4)
      - Mid-Atlantic Regional Office
        - Correspondence, 1989-1990 (Box 414, Folder 5)
        - Lease, 1989 (Box 414, Folder 6)
        - Regional Conference, 1990 February 5 (Box 414, Folder 7)
        - Moving, 1989 (Box 414, Folder 8)
      - Midwest Regional Office
        - Correspondence, 1989-1990 (Box 414, Folder 9)
        - Regional Conference, 1990 March 9-11 (Box 414, Folder 10)
        - Leases (Box 414, Folder 11)
      - Minutes Special Meetings, 1982-1985 (Box 414, Folder 12)
        (Mostly on a Director’s Meeting on the Membership, 1985)
      - Mirror Image, Inc., 1994-1995 (Box 414, Folder 13)
        (Merchandizing)
      - Mount Auburn Presbyterian Church, Cincinnati, Ohio--Lease, 1989 (Box 414, Folder 14)
      - National Advisors, 1986-1987 (Box 414, Folder 15)
        (AKA National Advisory Council (NAC) )
      - National Charities Information Bureau, 1976-1994, (3 Folders) (Box 414, Folder 16-18)
        (Reports on AIUSA)
      - National Sections
        - National Section Resources and Activities, 1978 (Box 414, Folder 19)
        - Annual reports to IEC, 1982 (Box 414, Folder 20)
        - Other sections--correspondence, 1990-1991 (Box 414, Folder 21)
      - Nemec, Jan--Torture Film, 1984 (Box 414, Folder 22)
      - New Orleans Video Access Center, 1979 (Box 414, Folder 23)
      - New York Office--Leases and Moves, 1970-1994, (5 Folders) (Box 414, Folder 24-28)
      - Northeast Regional Office
        - Contracts and Leases, 1987, (2 Folders) (Box 414, Folder 29-30)
        - Correspondence, 1989-1990 (Box 414, Folder 31)
        - Regional Conference, 1990 February 24 (Box 414, Folder 32)
      - Participation in political campaigns by AIUSA, 1986 (Box 414, Folder 33)
        (Legal issues related to)
      - Peat Marwick Main and Company
        - Management study of financial needs of AIUSA, 1988 (Box 414, Folder 34)
        - AIUSA Finance Office Review and AIUSA Regional Office Review, 1988-1989 (Box 414, Folder 35)
      - Personnel
        - Job descriptions, circa 1984 (Box 414, Folder 36)
        - Policies, 1991 (Box 414, Folder 37)
      - Personnel Policy Committee (PPC), 1984-1991, (9 Folders) (Box 415, Folder 1-9)
        (Includes meeting minutes and material on affirmation action and sexual harassment)
      - Philadelphia Satellite Office, 1988-1990 (Box 415, Folder 10)
      - Planning and priorities, 1986-1988 (Box 415, Folder 11)
      - Pooled Income Fund--procedures for establishing, Undated (Box 415, Folder 12)
      - Pracko Project, 1986-1987 (Box 415, Folder 13)
        (Fundraising proposal)
      - Reebok Human Rights Award, 1988-1993 (Box 415, Folder 14)
      - Records retention, 1990 (Box 415, Folder 15)
      - Refugees, 1981-1982 (Box 415, Folder 16)
        (includes AIUSA Refugee Handbook, policies, etc.)
      - Regional Action Networks (RANs), 1981-1982 (Box 415, Folder 17)
        (includes information on how RANs started)
      - Regional conferences, 1982 (Box 415, Folder 18)
        (Tips for planning, by Robert Maurer)
      - Regional finances, 1983 (Box 415, Folder 19)
      - Regional Membership Coordinators (RMCs), 1982-1983 (Box 415, Folder 20)
      - Regional organizing, 1980-1982 (Box 415, Folder 21)
      - Registration as a foreign agent, 1987 (Box 415, Folder 22)
        (US law as pertaining to AIUSA)
      - Relief, 1979-1987, (3 Folders) (Box 415, Folder 23-25)
      - Restricted funds, 1986 (Box 415, Folder 26)
      - Role of Nationals in AI activities, 1985-1986 (Box 415, Folder 27)
        (Restrictions for nationals in doing AI work on their country of origin, etc.)
      - Sandosham, Surita--Job Description for Executive Assistant to the Deputy Executive Director For Finance and Administration, 1995 (Box 415, Folder 28)
      - San Francisco Office--Leases and Search for Space, 1974-1992, (2 Folders) (Box 415, Folder 29-30)
      - Satellite Offices, 1988-1990, (2 Folders) (Box 415, Folder 31-32)
        (includes reports)
      - Schedule of consultants over $250--Current Contracts, 1992 (Box 415, Folder 33)
      - Southern Regional Office, 1986, 1989-1990, (2 Folders) (Box 415, Folder 34-35)
      - Staff memos, 1992 (Box 415, Folder 36)
        (Mainly related to budget cuts)
      - Student Human Rights Exchange (SHARE)--Meeting, 1992 (Box 415, Folder 37)
      - Summer Interns, 1982-1983 (Box 415, Folder 38)
      - Target Sector Work, 1982-1983
        - General (Box 415, Folder 39-40)
        - Medical (Box 415, Folder 41)
        - Minorities (Box 415, Folder 42)
        - Union Letters (Box 415, Folder 43)
      - Taxes--501 (c) (4) Possibilities, 1988-1989 (Box 416, Folder 1)
      - Trademark Issues, 1988-1991, (2 Folders) (Box 416, Folder 2-3)
      - Training Program, 1981-1982, (5 Folders) (Box 416, Folder 4-8)
      - Transfer of funds to International Secretariat--Legal Issues, 1986 (Box 416, Folder 9)
      - Travel
        - Contracts, 1984-1991 (Box 416, Folder 10)
        - Expenses, 1990-1993 (Box 416, Folder 11)
        - MVI Travel Management Services--Proposal, 1994 (Box 416, Folder 12)
      - United Nations (UN)
        - 1979, 1982 (Box 416, Folder 13)
        - World Conference on Human Rights (Vienna), 1993, (4 Folders) (Box 416, Folder 14-17)
      - UN Plaza (777)--Leases, 1977-1986 (Box 416, Folder 18)
      - Universal Declaration of Human Rights (Video Animation)--Contracts, 1991-1992 (Box 416, Folder 19)
      - Urgent Action office, Colorado--Lease, 1984- (Box 416, Folder 20)
      - Urgent Actions, 1983 (Box 416, Folder 21)
        (Memo and proposal for WARN)
      - Washington, D.C. Office
        - 1968-1988, (5 Folders) (Box 416, Folder 22-26)
        - Building, 1988-1991, (2 Folders) (Box 416, Folder 27-28)
        - Correspondence, 1989-1990 (Box 416, Folder 29)
      - Weissbrodt Agreement Re: A.I. Minnesota Lawyers Group, 1985 (Box 416, Folder 30)
      - Western Regional Office--Los Angeles, CA
        - Leases, 1974-, (2 Folders) (Box 416, Folder 31-32)
        - Correspondence, 1988-1990 (Box 416, Folder 33)
      - Women Prisoners of Conscience (AIUSA), 1982 March (Box 418, Folder 2)
      - Loose/Unfiled, 1980-1982, (3 Folders) (Box 418, Folder 3-5)
      - Loose/Unfiled, 1990-1994, (3 Folders) (Box 418, Folder 6-8)